#### Contact

0936123896 (Home) ntnpro@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kenz-nguyen (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

PHP

Magento

Node is

## Languages

English (Professional Working)
Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

CERTIFIED DEVELOPER AND DEVELOPER PLUS

# Ken Nguyen

Senior Developer NodeJs, ReactJs, PHP, AWS, Kubernetes Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Summary

Experienced on the website and mobile app development for over 10 years, specializing on Magento, NodeJs, ReactJs, PHP, Golang, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS.

As a Technical Architect, I'm responsible for complex E-Commerce development & also in charge of giving the team technical instructions across all of the projects and assist in the team for technical solutions

# Experience

#### Care

Senior Software Engineer September 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months) Vietnam

- Develop Healthcare features on the REST APIs and implement Kubernetes infrastructure are fast, reliable and scalable.
- Lead and develop the Streaming projects about Video Call, SocketIO, Live content, etc.
- Develop UnitTest, Code review, Assure performance of production.

Technology: Nest.js/Node.js, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Docker, CI Pipelines, AWS Kubernetes(EKS)

Lusso Enterprise Technical Architect January 2019 - July 2021 (2 years 7 months) Vietnam

### Roles and responsibilities:

- Build a developers team want to be part of; create a culture where achieving results/ exceeding goals; continually improving on behalf of customers; rewarding/ providing advancement opportunities to top performers happens at every level.
- Perform a technical analysis of requirements, apply SOLID principle, Design Patterns

- Lead a team of talented developers (front-end and back-end) and other designers and tech partners to ensure the excellence of the tech execution to achieve a seamless and scalable product.
- Review and development the overall tech architecture and integration with Website/Applications of company.
- Work closely with CEO, a successful serial entrepreneur and develop your skills with a diverse, international company

Technology: Node.js, React.js, Golang, Kubernetes, ElasticSeach

Isobar Commerce
Technical Lead
July 2012 - January 2019 (6 years 7 months)
Ho Chi Minh

Roles and responsibilities:

- Analyse and define clients' business strategy and determine system architecture requirements to achieve business goals.
- Manage code quality of Magento implementation projects for high fashion clients.
- Develop data architecture design to facilitate targeted customer analysis.
- Liaise with MNC client's headquarter / country e-commerce heads and different technology partners to work on multi-site implementations and ensure timely and quality deliverables
- Work with technical teams to ensure proposed solutions fulfill clients needs
- Support sales teams to achieve the sales objectives of e-commerce implementation.

Technology: PHP, Nginx, Scaling Apache, Magento Enterprise, NodeJs, MySQL(EAV model, Scaling Web Databases with MySQL Cluster)

Forix
Senior Magento Developer
March 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 5 months)
Hochiminh

Roles and responsibilities:

- Development large ecommerce projects and ensure their deliveries are on time and within budget. Report status and escalate issues as necessary to senior management through scheduled project steering committee meetings.

- Design and implement new systems by conducting requirement analysis, architecture and system design, infrastructure planning and project management. Manage multi-site development teams and external vendors in project delivery.
- Line manager for technical teams and provide support and advice as necessary. Participate in IT governing committees to prioritize new initiatives and provide architecture advices.

## Education

**Lotus University** 

Associate's Degree, Computer Programming · (2008 - 2011)